Inventory of the Ada Morse Grose papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ada Morse Grose papers
1915-1950
1915-1917
XX145
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 1 envelope, 1 album box, 1 oversize box (2.8 linear feet)
Typescript, correspondence, reports, passports, news clippings, handwritten notes, memorabilia, and photographs, relating to the peace movement during World War I.
Grose, Ada Morse, 1874-1959
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Ada Morse Grose (1874-1959) was the secretary to David Starr Jordan, first president of Stanford University, and Assistant General Secretary to the Henry Ford Peace Expedition and Neutral Conference for Continuous Mediation.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection centers on Ada Morse Grose's participation in the Henry Ford Peace Expedition and Neutral Conference for Continuous Mediation with the majority of the collection consisting of photographs and her writings, which include additional notes, news clippings, reports, and correspondence. Also included in the collection are Grose's personal passports and memorabilia from the Expedition.
Related Collection(s)
Lewis A. Maverick papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Alice Parks papers, 1883-1957, Hoover Institution Archives
David Starr Jordan papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931.; Henry Ford Peace Expedition.; Pacifism.; Peace.; United States--Neutrality.; World War, 1914-1918--Peace.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.
- Writings, 1915-1950
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of typescript drafts, reports, research notes, correspondence, and news clippings relating to the Expedition and conference.
  - "Henry Ford's Neutral Conference," bound typescript, undated (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Typescript, drafts, undated (Box-folder 1:2-3)
  - Typescript and expedition material, 1915-1950 (Box-folder 1:4-5)
- Photographs, 1915-1917
  Consists of photographs and one album relating to the Henry Ford Peace Expedition through Norway, the Netherlands, and Sweden.
  - Trip to Europe and Ford Peace Bureau, photo album, 1915-1917 (Album box)
  - 12 photographs depicting conference offices and people of the Henry Ford Peace Expedition, 1915, 1916 (Envelope A)
- Memorabilia, 1915-1917
  - Passports and citizenship registration, 1915-1917 (Box 2)
  - Briefcase and pins, undated (Box 2)